## **CONTACT ME**

Aman Jain 516, Stewart Avenue Ithaca, NY 14850

+1 607 379 0616

aj644@cornell.edu, aman.454@gmail.com

#### SUMMARY

M. Eng. (Operation Research and Information engineering) candidate at Cornell. Consistent high performer in academics. Gold medalist in MBA. Nuclear Engineer and Trained finance professional (CFA Level 3) in previous lives. Proficient in data skills, tools and data modeling. Published papers and worked as Teaching assistant in past. Multiple Academic and professionals awards. Love building products, teams and businesses. Early stage product management at - 2 now unicorns and 1 profitable SAAS business. Continuous self learner, traveler, cricketer and learning to mentor.

## **MEDIA MENTIONS**

Talking about new partner app

Driver experience journey

Swiggy stores launch

Swiggy Daily launch

Swiggy Go Teaser

News article for partner app revamp

Sports section, national newspaper

# INTERNATIONAL

- ASEAN region, Grab.com, Product management team (Singapore, Indonesia, Thailand, Malaysia, Philippines, Vietnam 2017)
- MENA region Market research for hyperlocal logistics play - UAE, Saudi and Egypt. (2019)

# **AMAN JAIN**

M.ENG. (ORIE),
CORNELL UNIVERSITY

## **EDUCATION**

**CORNELL UNIVERSITY** 

M.Eng. (Operation Research and Information Engineering) | 2019-20

INDIAN INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT, LUCKNOW

Gold medal in Master of Business Administration | 2012-14

BIRLA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY AND SCIENCE, PILANI CAMPUS,

Bachlor of Engineering (Hons) (9.47/10) | 2005-09

## **ACADEMIC ACHIEVEMENTS**

INDIAN INSTITUTE OF MANAGEMENT, LUCKNOW

- Hari Shankar Singhania Gold medal, Class of 2014.
- "Class of 1993 scholarship" for consistent academic excellence throughout 2 years
- Certificate of merit for academics during 5 trimesters.
- Awarded Lion's award for outstanding contribution to student body at IIM Lucknow.
- Top10 rank in APAC region in Bloomberg aptitude test for finance.

BIRLA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY AND SCIENCE, PILANI CAMPUS,

- Merit Scholarship for all 4 years at BITs Pilani for consistent academic performance
- Teaching assistant for 2 semesters aiding Professors in their academic routine
- Won multiple robotics and other technical and business competitions.
- Published 4 Academic Papers in decision making and manufacturing domain.

#### PAPER PRESENTED

- Gunjan Soni, Aman Jain. "Comparing traditional and JIT manufacturing in the supply chain", Presented at India Society of Manufactures, Nov. 2007
- Atul Khattar, Aman Jain. "A Methodological framework for evaluating the effectiveness of fly ash bricks using ANP". Presented at BITS Pilani, March 2008.
- Aman Jain, Manoj Thota, Raven Kumar. "Experimental, Analytical and Numerical analysis
  of stability of PFBR's main vessel under seismic load". Presented at BITS Pilani, March
  2008

# CERTIFICATION

- Online courses:
  - i. Machine learning by Andrew Ng (Coursera, 2019)
  - ii. Applied Data Science Specialization (IBM on Coursera, 2019)
  - iii Machine learning nano degree program supervised, unsupervised, deep learning
  - . and reinforcement learning. (Udacity, 2017)
- Passed CFA Exam Level 1,2 and 3, Dec 2012-June 2014.
- NSE (National Stock Exchange) Certification in Financial Markets (Advanced) and Equity derivatives, Aug 2012

## **ACADEMIC INTERNSHIPS**

#### Indira Gandhi Centre for atomic research (May-July 2007)

- Buckling of reactor vessels data modeling (for buckling models), complex mathematics, experimentation, statistics and data analysis.
- Deployed computer simulations for buckling of thin shells using FEM (finite element method) and used experimental set up to fine tune simulations.

#### Indian Institute of Technology - Kanpur, 2008

- Successfully complete the working model of thermal water purifier.
- Took part in feasibility analysis on mass industrial scale. Implemented a prototype at a glass factory compound in Firozabad.

## LEADERSHIP IN STUDENT LIFE

- Student leadership Elected as Academic Secretary for class of 2014, Head of Convocation Committee. Active in mechanical engineering society, BITS Pilani.
- Sports leadership Captain of college teams, Got mentioned in national newspaper for good performances.
- National service Scheme Tutored 150+students from nearby villages of Pilani.
- Enthusiast about Water sports and trekking.

## PRODUCT CONSULTING

Bounce share, Bangalore, July 2019

Operational products around Fleet engagement and Task management to drive higher availability and reduce operational costs.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Data SQL, Data visualization and analysis, Data modeling, simulation.
- Programming Python, VBA (MS Excel Macros), Google spreadsheet macros. MS office tools
- Product Management UI/UX, Scrum, User research, Product market fit, Product discovery, Experimentation.
- Finance Financial modeling, pricing, P&L and cash flow managements.
- Design wire-framing Canva, Balsamic, invision, mockflow

# **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Long term vision
- Ownership
- Experimentation & Data driven decision making
- Problem solving
- Customer obsession
- Written Communication
- People skills
- Team Building

# DAY IN LIFE

- Product Vision & Roadmapping -20%
- Business team 15%
- Engineering and Architect 15%
- UI/UX 10%
- Data 10%
- Mentoring and Reviews 20%
- CXOs 10%

## **ONLINE PRESENCE**

- http://amanjain454.com/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/aman -jain-1049188/
- https://github.com/amanjain454
- https://www.facebook.com/aman4
   54
- https://medium.com/@amanjain\_3 5652

## **RELEVANT COURSEWORK**

#### Indian Institute of Management, Lucknow 2012-14

• Decision Science courses (data analysis, modeling and optimization tools and techniques)
Quantitative analysis for manager, Management Information systems, Business intelligence
and Data mining, Quantitative application in finance, Game theory and application, Course
of independent studies (R Programming), Spreadsheet modeling (VBA Programming)

#### Birla Institute of Technology and Science (BITS), Pilani 2005-09

- Mathematics Mathematics 1,2 and 3, Numerical Analysis, Finite Element Method (ME G512)
- Decision science Probability and statistics, Optimization, Operation research
- Computer Programming Computer programming 1 and 2 (C programming), Computer Projects (Matlab Programming)

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# DIRECTOR, PRODUCT MANAGER

## Swiggy.com, Bangalore | Aug 2015 - Feb 2017 and August 2017 - July 2019

Among first product managers to join Swiggy when it was an early stage start up, contributed to its growth to a unicorn by 2018. Built products to lead 100X business growth. Consistently got outstanding ratings and rose to Director of Product management. Annual performance award for 2016 & 2018.

#### TEAM BUILDING

- Led a team of 8 PMs across these teams.
- Contributed towards building teams for Technology, Product, UI/UX, product operations, product analytics, user research and Operations. Strength grew from 5 to 100+.

#### LAUNCHING NEW BUSINESS LINES

- Built (all "0 to 1" initiatives) and Launched Swiggy stores (Hyperlocal grocery and general need service), Swiggy Daily (Lunch/Dinner subscription service) and Swiggy Go (Hyperlocal B2C and C2C logistics service).
- Led conceptualization, product discovery, user and market research, customer journeys, product development. Operational strategy, Go to market strategy and product market fit.

# DELIVERY PARTNER EXPERIENCE

- Build suit of products to enable over 150,000 delivery partners across India who deliver more than million orders a day. Build products around earning improvement, transparency, self serve, gamification and engagement.
- Improved longer logins by 7%, move NPS score from -0.4 to +0.2 over 6 months, Reduced orders rejected by drivers from 15% to 8%.

#### LOGISTICS ENGINE

- This Data driven product suit has been differentiating factor for the company taking care of short and long term capacity management, real time serviceability, partner assignment, queueing, batching etc.
- Increased delivery partner efficiency (order per hour per partner) by 40%, reduced empty legs by 10% and reduced waiting time of executive at restaurant by 15%.

#### PRODUCT MANAGER

# Grab.com, Singapore | Feb 2017 - August 2017

- Product roadmap to consolidate grabs' web properties spread across Singapore, Indonesia, Thailand, Malaysia, Philippines and Vietnam.
- Product owner for grab parcel initiative doing more than 10k orders a day in Jakarta, Indonesia.

#### PRODUCT MANAGER

## Moveinsync.com, Bangalore | Jan 2015 - Aug 2015

Moveinsync.com offers automated employee transportation solutions and counts google, Microsoft etc among its clientele. Worked on the product suit to improve efficiency of logistics operations.

• Ideal empty leg by 20% and corresponding savings in cost. Shuttle routing, automated vendor allocation, fleet planning tools, Automated billing – reduced manpower requirement by 60%.